Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 1. Reel-to-Reel audio tape, 1934 - 1981; 1; Boxes: 1744 - 1818
  - Subseries 1.2: The Best Years, 1979 - 1981; 1.2; Boxes: 1749 - 1757
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.05, Box 1753)
      141. S.S. Van Dyke 142. Renoir 143. Disraeli 144. Ziegfeld 145. Bob Hope 146. Marshall McLuhan 147. Sam Snead 148. John Wanamaker 149. John Witherspoon 150. Chaney Lake
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.06, Box 1753)
      151. Rose Kennedy 152. Lord Thompson 153. Richard Rodgers 154. Noah Webster 155. Irving and Electra Johnson 156. Marjorie Post 157. Billy Wilder 158. Tennis 159. The Bakers 160. George Mardikian
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.07, Box 1753)
      161. Elsie Woodward 162. Maurice Robinson 163. Louise Nevelson 164. Rosa Bonheur 165. Hazel Wightman 166. John Diefenbacher 167. Cato the Censor 168. Colonel Sanders 169. Malcolm Forbes 170. Marriage Centenary
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.08, Box 1753)
      231. Margaret Mead 232. Robert Montgomery 233. Sports after fifty 234. I.M. PEI 235. Queen Isabella 236. Harriet Atwood 237. George Pierrot 238. Arthur Rubinstein 239. Eva Jessye 240. Margaret Chase Smith
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.09, Box 1753)
      241. Martha Washington 242. George Sand 243. John Buchan 244. Pope Pius the Twelfth 245. Agatha Christie 246. Claude Pepper 247. Buckstein Charlie 248. Edith Sitwell 249. Herman Smith-Johannsen 250. Age of Adventure
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.10, Box 1753)
      251. Amelia Earhart 252. Mrs. Pankhurst 253. George M. Cohan 254. Paul Harris 255. Dorothy Sayers 256. Alton Ochsner 257. Dimitri Tiomkin 258. Georgia O’Keefe 259. Charles Atlas 260. Richard Reinke
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.11, Box 1753)
      261. Chick Evans 262. Betsy Miller 263. Fred Waring 264. Norman Cousins 265. Krishnamurti 266. Gordon Powell 267. Lise Meitner 268. Robertson Moses 269. May Chinn 270. George Burns
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.12, Box 1753)
      301. Lew Grade 302. Howard Shepherd 303. Space and Age 304. Adelina Patti 305. Mary Baker Eddy 306. Jack Dempsey 307. Cary Grant 308. Lady Montagu 309. Ardeth Evitt 310. Albert Schweitzer
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.13, Box 1753)
      311. David Niven 312. Elizabeth White 313. Pavlova 314. Lillian Wald 315. Henry Ford 316. Allen Dulles 317. Zenobia 318. Fanny Burney 319. Philip Whitcomb 320. Howard Kershner
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.14, Box 1753)
      321. George Pierrot 322. Alice Roosevelt Longworth 323. Isamu Noguchi 324. Oscar Hammerstein 325. Barbara Cartland 326. Women 327. Ollie Randall 328. Owen Wister 329. Nettie Rosenstein 330. Jam Handy
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.15, Box 1753)
      331. Molotov 332. James Wallace 333. Mildred Cable 334. Janet Gaynor 335. John Herbert 336. Retirement 337. Frauds 338. Pope John Paul II 339. Muriel Humphrey 340. Abigail Adams
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.16, Box 1753)
      341. Columbus 342. Estee Lauder 343. Eamon De Valera 344. Babe Didrikson Zaharias 345. Flora Lewis 346. Joseph Conrad 347. Joan Miro 348. Mae West 349. Jesse Owens 350. Harold Stassen
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.17, Box 1753)
      351. Lotte Lenya 352. Billie Jean King 353. Jackie Onassis 354. Ruth Hill 355. Francis Robinson 356. Smith Johnson 357. Debbie Reynolds 358. Jacob Javits 359. Millicent Fenwick 360. Gladys Straus
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1753.18, Box 1753)
      361. Jimmy Stewart 362. Melville Crane 363. Hanna Gray 364. Coors Brothers 365. Edna Ferber 366. Executives 367. William Paley 368. Lord Thomas 369. A. F. Willat 370. Genevieve Murphy
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.01, Box 1754)
      371. Bob Miner 372. Graying America 373. Ruth Handler 374. Henry Miller 375. Arthur and Kathryn Murray 376. Walter Hagen 378. Benjamin Disraeli 379. Dorothy Delay 380. Laurel and Hardy
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.02, Box 1754)
      381. Mailman 382. Miriam MacMillan 383. Bob and Joanne Herring 384. Warren Pershing 385. Georgiana Sibley 386. Baron von Steuben 387. Harold Coolidge 388. Billy Butlin 389. Roger Wilson 390. John Wooden
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.03, Box 1754)
      391. Dan Nauman 392. Empress Eugenie 393. Rosa Ponselle 394. Ronald Reagan 395. Frank Sinatra 396. Camels 397. Rachel Crothers 398. Emily Dickinson 399. Helen Gahagan Douglas 400. Sultan of Oman
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.04, Box 1754)
      401. Etienne Dupuch 402. Thomas Jefferson 403. Isabella Cannon 404. Lola Montez 405. Joe DiMaggio 406. Einstein 407. Melvyn Douglas 408. Sean O’Casey 409. Ronald Colman 410. Brad Washburn
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.05, Box 1754)
      411. Gene Kelly 412. Ann Zenger 413. Queen Mother 414. Juan Trippe 415. Jose Iturbi 416. Elizabeth Vining 417. Rose Kennedy - Part II 418. Dore Schary 419. Margaret Rutherford 420. Alexander Fleming
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.06, Box 1754)
      421. Frank Woolworth 422. Lawrence Welk 423. Fannie Hurst 424. Queen Mary 425. Sven Hedin 426. Edward Harriman 427. Averell Harriman 428. Maria Montessori 429. Grace Tully 430. Charlie Diuguid
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.07, Box 1754)
      431. Rex Stout 432. John Wesley 433. Evonne Goolagong 434. Sir Thomas Lipton 435. Mary Leakey 436. Douglas Fairbanks 437. Fred and Evelyn Jacob 438. Ginger Rogers 439. Anita Loos 440. Max Fisher
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.08, Box 1754)
      441. James Montgomery Flagg 442. Peter Townsend 443. Eva Le Gallienne 444. Anthony Eden 445. Boris Lissanevitch 446. Geoffrey Bell 447. Gene Sarazen 448. Gertrude Stein 449. Doris Bernays 450. Thomas E. Dewey
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.09, Box 1754)
      451. Hugh Downs 452. Senior Adulthood 453. Margaret Thatcher 454. Bob Headden 455. Picasso 456. Paul Robeson 457. Lillie Langtry 458. Marie Correlli 459. Judge Weinfeld 460. Fritz Wiessner
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.10, Box 1754)
      461. Audubon 462. Age Fifty-Five 463. Earle McAusland 464. General Simpson 465. Jean Piaget 466. Milton Eisenhower 467. Dorothy Sands 468. Lucretia Mott 469. Edward R. Murrow 470. Pancho Villa
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.11, Box 1754)
      471. Exercise and Age 472. Veronica Wedgewood 473. Older Women 474. Emperor Bokassa 475. Alexander Graham Bell 476. Alexander Haig 477. Tip O’Neill 478. Ella Fitzgerald 479. James McDonnell 480. Karsh
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.12, Box 1754)
      481. Sir Walter Scott 482. Age and Money 483. Ingrid Bergman 484. Don Fraser 485. Mikhail Vodopyanov 486. Katherine Anne Porter 487. Darryl Zanuck 488. Ulysses S. Grant 489. Helen Putnam 490. Barber
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.13, Box 1754)
      491. Henry Ford 492. Education and Age 493. Glenn Curtiss 494. Margaret Paston 495. Fritzi Scheff 496. Mary Baker Eddy 497. James Leftwich 498. Paul Draper 499. Margaret Truman Daniel 500. Lewis Strauss
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.14, Box 1754)
      501. Eubie Blake 502. Earle Clarke 503. Richard McDonald 504. Claudette Colbert 505. Stanley Reed 506. Train Robber 507. Theodore Kazimiroff 508. Woman Educators 509. Maria Mitchell 510. J. William Miller - Advisory Group
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.15, Box 1754)
      531. Zane Grey 532. Hattie Jessup 533. President Reagan 534. George Eliot 535. Edwin Teale 536. Joe Binns 537. Grant Scandals 538. Abe Horowitz 539. Catherine the Great 540. Bessie Carlson
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.16, Box 1754)
      541. Mae West 542. Eleanor Bridges 543. Tim McCoy 544. Andrew Jackson 545. Brooks Atkinson 546. Museum of Broadcasting 547. Joel Hildebrand 548. Doctor Cronin 549. Kathleen Nesbitt 550. Carl Akeley
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.17, Box 1754)
      551. Donald Douglas 552. Henry [Wihlein] Eline 553. Melvyn Douglas 554. Pat O’Brien 555. Hans Kraus 556. Walter Cronkite 557. Happy Chandler 558. Barbara Stanwyck 559. General Sherman 560. Jeannette Rankin
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1754.18, Box 1754)
      561. David Hearst 562. Elizabeth Friedman 563. Elton Trueblood 564. Harold Dodds 565. P.K. Gardner 566. Marshall McLuhan 567. Delia Brown 568. Linus Pauling 569. Athelstan Spilhaus 570. Yehudi Menuhin
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.01, Box 1755)
      581. Louise Boyd 582. John D. Rockefeller 583. Bob Orbin 584. David O. McKay 585. Joe Louis
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.02, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 2:59 1. Barbara Ward 1:02 3:08 2. George Jessel :51 2:46 3. Marlin Perkins 1:16 3:26 4. Carl von Hoffman 1:13 2:54 5. Rosa Ponselle :55 2:49 6. The Durants 1:07 2:52 7. Nathaniel Hawthorne :51 2:55 8. John McCormack :59 3:04 9. Anwar Sadat 1:01 2:44 10. Alistair Cooke :51
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.03, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 2:57 11. John Houston :44 1:53 12. Mickey Walker :58 2:57 13. Cozy Cole :57 2:53 14. Katherine Brand :55 3:02 15. Red Grange :56 3:02 16. Henry L. Stimson :58 3:08 17. Carroll of Carrollton :51 3:02 18. Nell Demorest :48 3:06 19. Carl Hubbell :58 3:04 20. Soong Sisters 1:53
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.04, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 3:05 21. Walter Judd :45 2:52 22. Anthony Quinn :42 2:51 23. Frances Perkins 1:02 2:58 24. Marsh Morrison :46 2:52 25. Nina Starr :48 2:48 26. Gifford Pinchot :48 3:04 27. Rudyard Kipling :55 2:54 28. John Jay :49 2:48 29. Ethelyn Hill :46 2:52 30. George du Maurier :48
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.05, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 2:38 31. Enid Lockhart :42 2:52 32. Virgil Thompson :49 2:44 33. Esther Lape :54 2:50 34. Sir Charles Forte :45 2:58 35. Elias Klein :59 2:59 36. General Freyberg :53 2:36 37. Sarah Kelly :39 2:54 38. Cervantes :55 2:55 39. Mortimer Adler :46 2:56 40. Margaret Mitchell 1:00
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.06, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 101. General Allenby 2:15 102. Count Zinzindorf 2:03 103. Lady Astor 2:05 104. Mary Pickford 2:09 105. Richard Francis Burton 2:10 106. John D. Rockefeller 2:02 107. George Meany 2:07 108. Claire Booth Luce 2:15 109. Robert Moses 2:02 110. Barbara Hutton 2:15
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.07, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 111. Alfred Crover 2:17 112. Fred Astaire 2:05 113. Bernt Balchen 2:12 114. Beulah Bondi 2:42 115. Milton Ager 1:47 116. Walter Winchell 1:51 117. Mary Cassatt 1:56 118. Mayer Guggenheim 1:57 119. Cicero 1:49 120. Frederick Crawford 1:50
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.08, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 171. Connie Mack 2:06 172. Irwin Stander 2:04 173. Paul Cadwell 2:06 174. Methuselah 2:01 175. Alva Gimbel 2:09 176. Lila Wallace 2:07 177. John McGraw 2:17 178. Jack Girsham 2:25 179. Josephine Baker 2:12 180. Casanova 2:14
    - Lowell Thomas The Best Years, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.09, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 181. Arlene Thomas 2:17 182. Patience Wright 2:09 183. Hunza 2:00 184. Samuel Newhouse 1:52 185. Garbo 2:06 186. Tetrazzini 1:55 187. Clare Booth Luce 1:55 188. John Wayne 1:54 189. Alice Roosevelt Longworth 1:58 190. Cecil Rhodes 2:02
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.10, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 191. John Galbraith 2:07 192. Bernard McDonough 2:19 193. Akio Morita 1:56 194. Thomas J. Watson Sr. 2:03 195. Thomas J. Watson Jr. 2:16 196. Frank Lloyd Wright 1:50 197. I.A. Richards 2:02 198. Rachel Carson 2:19 199. Helen Keller 2:08 200. Moses 2:23
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.11, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 201. Peggy Guggenheim 1:55 202. Frank Braynard 1:58 203. Peter Grace 1:55 204. Howard Jarvis 1:58 205. Evangeline Booth 1:52 206. Richard Wagner 1:49 207. Sonny Werblin 1:55 208. Adolph Ochs 1:50 209. Mary Brooks Picken 2:01 210. Aloise Buckley 1:54 Promos at End
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.12, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 211. Raymond Loewy 1:40 212. Marian Cooper 1:58 213. Amos Alonzo Stagg 1:46 214. Frances Trollope 1:43 215. Joy Adamson 1:51 216. Dorothy Parker 1:47 217. Eldon Tanner 1:48 218. Father Coughlin 1:56 219. Donald MacMillan 2:01 220. Kirsten Flagstad 1:49
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.13, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 221. Golda Meir 1:47 222. Diamond Anniversary 1:50 223. Paul Von Lettow -Vorbeck 1:53 224. Lewis Mumford 1:49 225. Alexandra Tolstoy 1:54 226. Lord Mountbatten 1:32 227. Dewitt Wallace 1:46 228. Edna Saint Vincent Millay 1:44 229. Roy Larsen 1:47 230. Clara Schumann 1:50
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.14, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 261. Chick Evans 1:28 262. Betsy Miller 1:38 263. Fred Waring 1:34 264. Norman Cousins 1:50 265. Krishnamurti 1:46 266. Gordon Powell 1:42 267. Lise Meitner 1:55 268. Robertson Moses 1:48 269. May Chinn 1:49 270. George Burns 1:56
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.15, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 271. Maggie Kuhn 1:52 272. Hamilton Fish 2:06 273. Tito 1:47 274. Martha Graham 1:36 275. Francis Robinson 1:42 276. Ho Ying-chin 1:53 277. Noah 1:47 278. Richard Rogers 1:36 279. Nonagenarians 1:46 280. May Hoag 1:50
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.16, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 411. Gene Kelly 1:50 412. Anna Zenger 2:00 413. Queen Mother 1:46 414. Juan Trippe 1:54 415. Jose Iturbi 1:49 416. Elizabeth Vining 1:52 417. Rose Kennedy 2:00 418. Dore Schary 1:54 419. Margaret Rutherford 1:46 420. Alexander Fleming 2:05
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.17, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 421. Frank Woolworth 1:49 422. Lawrence Welk 2:00 423. Fannie Hurst 1:39 424. Queen Mary 1:52 425. Sven Hedin 1:52 426. Edward Harriman 1:52 427. Averell Harriman 1:54 428. Maria Montessori 1:56 429. Grace Tully 1:50 430. Charlie Diuguid 1:45
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1755.18, Box 1755)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 431. Rex Stout 1:40 432. John Wesley 1:59 433. Evonne Goolagong 1:48 434. Sir Thomas Lipton 1:51 435. Mary Leakey 1:52 436. Douglas Fairbanks 1:50 437. Fred and Evelyn Jacob 1:52 438. Ginger Rogers 1:42 439. Anita Loos 2:10 440. Max Fisher 1:44
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.01, Box 1756)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 441. James Montgomery Flagg 1:40 442. Peter Townsend 1:54 443. Eva Le Gallienne 2:02 444. Anthony Eden 1:49 445. Boris Lissanevitch 2:07 446. Geoffrey 1:54 447. Gene Sarazen 1:48 448. Gertrude Stein 1:56 449. Doris Bernays 2:01 450. Thomas E. Dewey 1:56
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.02, Box 1756)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 451. Hugh Downs 1:58 452. Senior Adulthood 1:51 453. Margaret Thatcher 1:58 454. Bob Headden 2:00 455. Picasso 2:04 456. Paul Robeson 1:48 457. Lillie Langtry 2:01 458. Marie Corelli 2:00 459. Judge Weinfeld 1:52 460. Fritz Wiessner 2:00
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.03, Box 1756)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 471. Exercise and Age 1:56 472. Veronica Wedgewood 1:58 473. Older Women 1:56 474. Emperor Bokassa 1:52 475. Alexander Graham Bell 1:52 476. Alexander Haig 2:05 477. Tip O’Neill 1:56 478. Ella Fitzgerald 2:10 479. James McDonnell 1:46 480. Karsh 2:02
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.04, Box 1756)
      Time Overall Title of Feature Time Till Cue 481. Sir Walter Scott 1:50 482. Age and Money 1:50 483. Ingrid Bergman 1:54 484. Don Fraser 2:00 485. Mikhail Vodopyanov 2:00 486. Katherine Anne Porter 1:56 487. Darryl Zanuck 1:54 488. Ulysses S. Grant 2:00 489. Helen Putnam 1:59 490. Barber 1:44
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.05, Box 1756)
      101. Connie Mack 102. Irwin Stander 103. Paul Cadwell 104. Methuselah 105. Alva Gimbel 106. Lila Wallace 107. John McGraw 108. Jack Girsham 109. Josephine Baker 110. Casanova
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.06, Box 1756)
      111. Arlene Thomas 112. Patience Wright 113. Hunza 114. Samuel Newhouse 115. Garbo 116. Tetrazzini 117. Clare Booth Luce 118. John Wayne 119. Alice Roosevelt Longworth 120. Cecil Rhodes
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.07, Box 1756)
      121. John Galbraith 122. Bernard McDonough 123. Akio Morita 124. Thomas J. Watson, Sr. 125. Thomas J. Watson, Jr. 126. Frank Lloyd Wright 127. I.A. Richards 128. Rachel Carson 129. Helen Keller 130. Moses
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.08, Box 1756)
      131. Peggy Guggenheim 132. Frank Braynard 133. Peter Grace 134. Howard Jarvis 135. Evangeline Booth 136. Richard Wagner 137. Sonny Werblin 138. Adolph Ochs 139. Mary Brooks Picken 140. Aloise Buckley
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.09, Box 1756)
      211. Raymond Loewy 212. Marian Cooper 213. Amos Alonzo Stagg 214. Frances Trollope 215. Joy Adamson 216. Dorothy Parker 217. Eldon Tanner 218. Father Coughlin 219. Donald MacMillan 220. Kirsten Flagstad
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.10, Box 1756)
      211. Raymond Loewy 212. Merian Cooper 213. Amos Alonzo Stagg 214. Frances Trollope 215. Joy Adamson 216. Dorothy Parker 217. Eldon Tanner 218. Father Coughlin 219. Donald B. MacMillan 220. Kirsten Flagstad
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.11, Box 1756)
      141. Golda Meir 142. Diamond anniversary 143. Paul Von Lettow-Vorbeck 144. Lewis Mumford 145. Alexandra Tolstoy 146. Lord Mountbatten 147. DeWitt Wallace 148. Edna Saint Vincent Millay 149. Roy Larsen 150. Clara Schumann
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.12, Box 1756)
      231. Maggie Kuhn 232. Hamilton Fish 233. Tito 234. Martha Graham 235. Francis Robinson 236. Ho Ying-chin 237. Noah 238. Richard Rodgers 239. Nonagenarians 240. May Hoag
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.13, Box 1756)
      241. Darryl F. Zanuck 242. Voltaire 243. Henry J. Kaiser 244. Freya Stark 245. Johann Sebastian Bach 246. Roy Howard 247. Andre Kostelanetz 248. Mary Kingsley 249. Bismarck 250. Princess Irene
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.14, Box 1756)
      251. Myrna Loy 252. Age and happiness 253. Coco Chanel 254. Alfred Hitchcock 255. Fulton J. Sheen 256. A. P. Giannini 257. Hyman Rickover 258. Alf Landon 259. Duchess of Marlborough 260. Exy Johnson
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.15, Box 1756)
      511. Harriet Tubman 512. Emma Willard 513. Hattie Caraway 514. John Keenan 515. Jane Croly 516. Franklin Atwater 517. Helen Jepson 518. George Halas 519. George C. Scott 520. Harold Macmillan
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.16, Box 1756)
      521. Lord Ballantrae 522. Nellie Bly 523. Henrietta Swope 524. Marc Connelly 525. Princeton 526. Growing old 527. Willie Sutton 528. Roger Tory Peterson 529. Buddy Ebsen 530. John McCormack
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1756.17, Box 1756)
      571. Peggy Lind 572. William Beebe 573. Senior Citizens 574. Satchel Paige 575. Florence Daly 576. Efrem Zimbalist 577. Charles Ives 578. Colonel Sanders 579. Jean Reed 580. George Raft
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1757.01, Box 1757)
      1. General Jimmy Doolittle 2. Herbert Hoover 3. General Douglas MacArthur 4. Sir Hubert Wilkins 5. Bernard Baruch 6. Sir Winston Churchill 7. Somerset Maugham 8. Ben Franklin 9. John Foster Duller 10. Vice President Alben Barkley 11. Stefansson 12. Carnegie 13. Michelangelo 14. Holmes 15. Bernhardt 16. Burton 17. M. Martin 18. B. Russell 19. C. Vanderbilt 20. J. Adams 21. Produced by: Gladney Communications 919 Third Avenue New York, New York (212) 752-7150
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1757.02, Box 1757)
      1. Lowell Thomas station promotions at head of reel 1-23; 2-16; 3-22 2. 361 - Jimmy Stewart, 1:56 3. 362 - Melville Crane, 1:48 4. 363 - Hanna Gray, 1:58 5. 364 - Coors brothers, 2:07 6. 365 - Edna Ferber, 2:17 7. 366 - Executives, 1:56 8. 367 - William Paley, 2:08 9. 368 - Lord Thomas, 1:56 10. 369 - A. F. Willat, 1:45 11. 370 - Genevieve Murphy, 1:40
    - The Best Years with Lowell Thomas, circa 1979 - 1981 (Folder 1757.03, Box 1757)
      1. Lowell Thomas station promotions at head of reel 1-23; 2-16; 3-22 2. 371 - Bob Miner, 1:57 3. 372 - Graying America, 1:54 4. 373 - Ruth Handler, 2:09 5. 374 - Henry Miller, 1:46 6. 375 - Arthur and Kathryn Murray, 1:55 7. 376 - Walter Hagen, 2:26 8. 377 - Jack Simplot, 1:53 9. 378 - Benjamin Disraeli, 2:08 10. 379 - Dorothy Delay, 2:08 11. 380 - Laurel and Hardy, 1:46
  - Subseries 1.3: Tibet, 1949; 1.3; Boxes: 1757 - 1758
    - Tibet, 1949 July (Folder 1757.04, Box 1757)
      En route 1. Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Report from Bengal, India to Tibetan border 2. Lowell Thomas, Jr., report from Tehran July 19, 1949 3. Lowell Thomas in plane over Pacific, halfway to Hawaii July 21, 1949 4. Lowell Thomas interviews Bishop Baumgartner July 25, 1949 5. Lowell Thomas from Tokyo, interview with Emp. staff recorded July 29, 1949
    - Tibet, 1949 August (Folder 1757.05, Box 1757)
      1) Lowell Thomas from Tokyo. Interviews Diet Kamayama and Aitosomatso (August 8, 1949) 2) Lowell Thomas, Jr. repeats on prep. For Tibetan expo. (August 24, 1949) 3) Lowell Thomas from India (August 23, 1949) 4) Lowell Thomas, Jr. from Gangtok. Reports on Avalanche (August 30, 1949)
    - Tibet, 1949 August (Folder 1757.06, Box 1757)
      En route 1. Lowell Thomas, Sr. Reports on Emperor of Japan 2. Ride to Tokyo with Colonel Wheeler, Impressions on being side-swiped by bus 3. Letter to Mrs. Thomas
    - Tibet, 1949 August (Folder 1757.07, Box 1757)